Guide to the March, Middagh, and Sands families property records 1974.038
Brooklyn Historical Society
March, Middagh, and Sands families property records
1770-1856
1830-1850
Brooklyn Historical Society
Hicks family
Luquer family
Van Nostrand family
Sands family
March family
Middagh family
1974.038
0.5 Linear Feet in one box.
This collection includes bonds, correspondence, deeds, financial records, leases, mortgages, quit claims, and other legal documents relating to property held by the March, Middagh, and Sands families of Brooklyn.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Marion Litchfield, 1931.
Biographical note
The March, Middagh, and Sands families were allied multigenerational families who resided in Brooklyn.
Biographical note - Sands family
Joshua Sands (1757-1835) (brother of Comfort Sands, both sons of John Sands and Elizabeth Cornell, m. 1736) married, 1780, Ann Ayscough (aka, Anne Ayscough, Anne Askew, Ann Sands, Anne Sands) (1761-1851) (daughter of Dr. Richard Ayscough and Ann Langdon). Joshua Sands was a New York State Senator, 1791-1797, collector of the port of New York from 1797, president of the board of trustees of the village of Brooklyn in 1824, and a representative in the U.S. Congress in 1803-1805 and 1825-1827. He was a founding trustee of the Episcopal Church in Brooklyn (1787) which re-organized as St. Ann's Church in 1795. Both Joshua and his wife were long connected with this congregation, Ann being particulary active in charitable activities throughout her life. According to historian Henry Reed Stiles, Ann Sands also "was the principal founder and the first directress of the Louisian School and therefore, indirectly, was the founder of the first public school ever established in Brooklyn. She was, also, the president of the Brooklyn Dorcas Society." Their home appeared in Francis Guy's 1820 painting of a Winter Scene at Brooklyn (now in the collection of the Brooklyn Museum), as did the figure of Joshua Sands himself, in conversation with Augustus Graham.
Biographical note - Middagh family
Aert Middagh (circa 1707-1777) son of Gerrit Aertsen Middagh and Cornelia van Kowenhoven, married Magdalena Stryker (b. 1710), daughter of Jan Pieterse Stryker and Margretta Schenk, and they had children:
Maria Middagh (d. 1763) m. Samuel Hicks (b. 1725) (son of Samuel Hicks and Martha Doughty)
Gerrit Middagh (aka Gerrett Middagh) (b. circa 1731)
John Middagh (aka Jan Middagh) (circa 1733-1811) m. Sarah Ryerson (1763)
Margretta Middagh (b. circa 1735) (aka Margrita Middagh, Margaret Middagh) m. George Moore (1760)
Cornelia Middagh (b. circa 1737)
Magdalena Middagh (b. circa 1739) m. Volkert Sprong Jr. (1746-circa 1829) (1767)
Other Finding Aids
An analog version of this finding aid with more detail, including genealogical information on some of the families, is stored in the box with the collection.
Related Materials
Luquer family property records, 1866-1879 (1973.252)
Middagh family agreement, 1730 (1977.642)
Garrett Middagh papers, 1695-1758 (1977.654)
Sands family papers, 1776-1795 (ARC.096)
John Middagh account book (1974.027)
Middagh family papers (1974.179)
Scope and Contents
This collection includes bonds, correspondence, deeds, financial records, leases, mortgages, quit claims, and other legal documents relating to property held by the March, Middagh, and Sands families of Brooklyn. Most items originated with the estate of Aert Middagh (d. 1777) and then passed to the Sands and March families by descent or marriage. Some records refer to property in Jefferson County, N.Y. Also included are land records of members of the Hicks, Luquer, and Van Nostrand families, among others, and an 1838 report of commissioners appointed by the Kings County Board of Supervisors to inquire into the loaning of $79,000 received from U.S. revenue.
The bulk of the collection pertains to transactions involving Samuel B.M. Sands (1799-1835) and/or his nephew, Joshua S. March (1809-1842), both of whom married Magdalen Middagh (1808-1844), the daughter of Aert Middagh (ca. 1776-ca. 1815) and Martha Middagh (née Van Nostrand). The collection may have passed through the hands of John Middagh Sands (1827-1873), the son of Magdalen and Samuel B.M. Sands. Records also derive from Nicholas Luquer and his wife Sarah Lea Luquer (née Lynch), from George Hicks, and others.
Real property -- New York (State) -- Jefferson County; Reports; Real property -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Deeds; Financial records; Correspondence; Indentures; Land titles -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Mortgages; Leases; Families -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Land titles -- New York (State) -- Jefferson County; Deeds -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.); Hicks family; Middagh family; Luquer family; Van Nostrand family; Sands family; March family; Cowenhoven family; Luquer family; Mitchell Family; Van Nostrand family; Sands, Samuel B.M. (Bayard Malcolm), 1799-1835; Sands, Joshua; Sackett, Clarence; Sands, John
- Bond between Samuel B.M. Sands and Clarence D. Sackett, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bond between Samuel B.M. Sands and Albert Wyckoff, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bond between Joshua S. March and the Long Island Bank, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bond between Martha Middagh, Cyrus Porter Smith, and Abraham Van Nostrand, 1846 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Historical note
  These three individuals were executors of the will of Magdalen March.
- Bond between John M. Sands and Francis Mallaby, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Deed from Joseph Colwell to Frederick Mitchel, 1794 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Scope and Contents
  Deed from Joseph Colwell (aka Joseph Caldwell) and his wife Sarah Colwell (aka Sarah Caldwell, granddaughter of Art Middagh [aka Aert Middagh] through his daughter Margrita Middagh) to Frederick Mitchel (aka Frederick Mitchell), for land lying about a quarter of a mile from the Brooklyn Ferry, bordering the main village road and the properties of Valentine Swartzcop (aka Valentine Swertcope), Jacob Hicks, and Doctor Barbareen, witnessed by J. Roorbach, James E. Miller, Abraham Vanderveer (clerk, 1820), and John Ray.
- Deed from Theodosius Hunt to Frederick Mitchel, 1794 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Deed from Theodosius Hunt and his wife, Elizabeth Hunt (granddaughter of Art Middagh through his daughter Margrita Middagh) to Frederick Mitchel, for Elizabeth's portion of the above-named property (witnessed, as above).
- Deed from Nicholas Cowenhoven to Abraham Luquere, 1833 copy of 1784 original (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Deed conveying extensive lands in the township of Brooklyn from Nicholas Cowenhoven and his wife, Jannatie Cowenhoven, of New Utrecht, to Abraham Luquere (aka Abraham Luquer) of Bushwick, the land bordering on the properties of the late Hendrick Suydam, of Rynear Suydam (aka Reynier Suydam), John Van Dyck, Jacob Sebring Jr., John Rapalje, John Suydam, the deed's copy certified by Abraham Vanderveer, clerk.
- Deed from Samuel Sackett to his children, 1821 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Deed conveying land in the township of Brooklyn from Samuel Sackett to his children – Clarence D. Sackett, Grenville A. Sackett, and Elizabeth K. Sackett – the land received previously, by agreement (1809) between Dorothy Mitchell (widow and executrix of the will of her late husband, Frederick Mitchell) and Samuel Jackson, Samuel Sackett and George Hicks, this earlier agreement enforced by William Livingston, the deed witnessed by James B. Clarke, certified (1822) by John Garrison, and recorded (1823) by Abraham Vanderveer, clerk.
- Lease from Losee Van Nostrand to Charles Prince, 1824 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Lease conveying property at 209 Fulton Street, Brooklyn, from Losee Van Nostrand (guardian of Magdalen Middagh, Sarah Middagh, and Cornelia Middagh, the children and heirs of the late Aert Middagh) to Charles Prince, for a term of nine years, signed by both parties and witnessed by Angelina Van Nostrand and Almira Van Nostrand.
- Lease from Sarah Luquer to William Thomas, 1825 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Lease conveying property at the corner of Henry Street and Poplar Street in Brooklyn from Sarah Luquer to William Thomas, signed by both, and witnessed by Edward N. Duryea.
- Deed from Nicholas Luquer to Joshua Sands March, 1825 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Deed conveying several parcels of land in Brooklyn's 6th Ward from Nicholas Luquer and his wife Sarah Lea Luquer to Joshua Sands March, the deed signed by the Luquers and by Henry Cruse Murphy, and recorded in 1835.
- Deed from William R. Dean to George A. Hicks, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Deed conveying lots on Smith Street and Livingston Street in Brooklyn from William R. Dean and his wife Helen Dean to George A. Hicks, witnessed also by Joseph Dean.
- Lease from Sarah Luquer to John Sinclair, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Lease conveying a lot on Fulton Street, Brooklyn, from Sarah Luquer, widow, to John Sinclair, witnessed also by Robert Sinclair and Rebeca Ross.
- Deed from Robert Graves to Samuel B.M. Sands, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Deed conveying land on Smith Street, Brooklyn, from Robert Graves of New York to Samuel B.M. Sands of Brooklyn, witnessed also by Ann Graves, C. Walker, William P. Hallett, and Nicholas Dean.
- Deed from John Dean to Samuel B.M. Sands, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Deed conveying a parcel of land on the corner of Smith Street and Livingston Street, Brooklyn, from John Dean to Samuel B.M. Sands, witnessed also by W. Rockwell and Joseph Dean.
- Deed from George A. Hicks to Samuel B.M. Sands, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Deed conveying a house and lot on Livingston Street, Brooklyn, from George A. Hicks and his wife Caroline Hicks to Samuel B.M. Sands, witnessed also by Joseph Dean.
- Deed from Samuel Jackson and George Hicks to Clarence D. Sackett, 1831 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Quit-claim deed conveying land on Fulton Street in Brooklyn (which was originally devised by Aert Middagh to his daughters, Margaretta and Magdalena) from Samuel Jackson, George Hicks, and his wife Elizabeth Hicks, all of Brooklyn, to Clarence D. Sackett of New York, witnessed by Edward M.M. Clarke.
- Deed from Martha Middagh to Magdalen Sands, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Quit-claim deed conveying parcels of the Middagh estate in Brooklyn from Martha Middagh (née Van Nostrand) to her daughter, Magdalen Sands, the wife of Samuel B.M. Sands, referring to the chancery court action between Samuel and Magdalen Sands, as complainants, and William R. Gracie and wife Sarah Gracie, Charles J. Henshaw and wife Cornelia Henshaw, and Martha Middagh, as defendants, the deed signed by Martha Middagh and approved by N.B. Morse (Nathan B. Morse).
- Deed from Matthias Bruen to Samuel B.M. Sands, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Deed conveying land in Brooklyn, from Matthias Bruen of Perth Amboy, NJ, to Samuel B.M. Sands, witnessed by Robert G. Rankin and Abraham Asten.
- Deed from William R. Gracie to Samuel B.M. Sands, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Quit-claim deed conveying a lot on Henry Street in Brooklyn from William R. Gracie and his wife Sarah Gracie of the Town of Jamaica, Queens, NY, to Samuel B.M. Sands of Brooklyn, witnessed by N.B. Morse.
- Release from William Laurence to Samuel B.M. Sands, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Release conveying two lots of the Middagh estate in Brooklyn from William Laurence of New York to Samuel B.M. Sands, witnessed by G.G. Van Wagenen.
- Deed from Nicholas Luquer to Samuel B.M. Sands, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Quit-claim deed conveying land on Fulton Street, Brooklyn, adjacent to the lands of the John Middagh estate, from Nicholas Luquer and his wife Sarah Lea Luquer to Samuel B.M. Sands, witnessed by Joseph Dean.
- Deed from Silas Butler to Samuel B.M. Sands, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Warrantee deed conveying land on Sands Street (formerly of the estate of Ebenezer Stevens) in Brooklyn from Silas Butler and his wife Phoebe Butler to Samuel B.M. Sands, witnessed by Edward M.M. Clarke.
- Deeds from Charles J. Henshaw to Samuel B.M. Sands, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Two quit-claim deeds conveying lands on the former Middagh estate and at the corner of Fulton and Clinton Streets in Brooklyn from Charles J. Henshaw and his wife Cornelia Henshaw to Samuel B.M. Sands, witnessed by N.B. Morse.
- Deed from Charles J. Henshaw to Magdalen Sands, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Deed conveying land on Cranberry Street, Brooklyn, from Charles J. Henshaw and his wife Cornelia Henshaw, with consent of Martha Middagh, to Magdalen Sands, widow, witnessed by Henry Cruse Murphy.
- Lease from Samuel B.M. Sands to Stephen Sutton and Henry D. Young, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Lease for land between Fulton and Poplar Streets adjoining Buckbee's Alley in Brooklyn, from Samuel B.M. Sands to Stephen Sutton and Henry D. Young, possibly witnessed by Cyrus Porter Smith.
- Deed from Jacob Brantingham to Joshua Sands March, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Deed conveying a block of 34 parcels bounded by Columbia, Mill, Betts and Centre Streets in Brooklyn, from Jacob Brantingham and his wife Cornelia Brantingham of New York to Joshua Sands March.
- Deed for land formerly conveyed by Nicholas Luquer, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Deed, as above, for land formerly conveyed by Nicholas Luquer, this deed witnessed by Washington Cockle, with amendmants by Joshua Sands March.
- Deed from Joshua Sands March to Clement Dudley March, 1836 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Deed conveying land on Brooklyn Heights from Joshua Sands March to his brother Clement Dudley March, witnessed by Henry Cruse Murphy.
- Deed from Clement Dudley March to Joshua Sands March, 1836 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Deed, as above, the parties reversed, witnessed by John Smalley.
- Deed from Charles J. Henshaw, Cornelia Henshaw, and Martha Middagh to Joshua Sands March, 1836 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Deed conveying 27 lots on Brooklyn Heights from Charles J. Henshaw, his wife Cornelia Henshaw, and Martha Middagh, to Joshua Sands March, witnessed by Henry Cruse Murphy.
- Deed from Joshua Sands March to Clement D. March, 1838 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Deed conveying lots in Brooklyn's Third Ward from Joshua Sands March and his wife Magdalen March (née Middagh) to Clement D. March, witnessed by their brother Thomas H. March and Samuel Garrison. Contains Middagh family data.
- Deed from Clement D. March to Joshua Sands March, 1838 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Deed, similar to the above, the parties reversed, witnessed by Samuel Garrison.
- Chancery Court Reports re: Sands vs. Gracie, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Report by the Commissioners (Ralph Malbone, Joseph B. Henshaw, and Cyrus Hitchcock), copy, partitioning and appraising lands in Brooklyn for the Chancery Court, re: Samuel B.M. Sands and his wife Magdalen Sands vs. William R. Gracie and his wife Sarah Gracie, Charles J. Henshaw and his wife Cornelia Henshaw, and Martha Middagh, the report witnessed by Joseph Dean, copy made by John Walworth; Response to the Commissioners' report, re: the above matter before the Chancery Court, at New York, William T. McCoun presiding, a partial copy.
- Deed from Thomas H. March to Joshua Sands March, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Quit-claim deed conveying land in Ogle County, Illinois, from Thomas H. March to Joshua Sands March.
- Deed from Norris M. Woodruff to William M. Sands, 1821 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Deed conveying land in Sacket's Harbor, Jefferson County, NY, from Norris M. Woodruff and his wife Roxanna T. Woodruff, of Watertown, Jefferson Co., NY, to William Malcolm Sands of Houndsfield, Jefferson Co., NY.
- Deed from Elijah Field Jr. to William M. Sands, 1821 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Deed conveying land at Sackets Harbor, NY, from Elijah Field Jr. and his wife Esther Field to William M. Sands, all of that place.
- Deed from Melancthon T. Woolsey to William M. Sands, 1822 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Deed conveying land at Sackets Harbor, NY, from Melancthon T. Woolsey and his wife Susan Cornelia Woolsey to William M. Sands, all of that place.
- Deed from John M. Sands to Jesse C. Dann, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Warranty deed conveying land at Sackets Harbor, NY, from John Middagh Sands and his wife Esther Sands (née Esther Stevens Holt) of Flushing, Queens County, NY, to Jesse C. Dann of Sackets Harbor, the land encumbered by a mortgage executed by William M. Sands and his wife Elizabeth Sands (née Breese) to Francis Mallaby, the deed witnessed at Brooklyn by James Howard and verified by Francis B. Stryker.
- Deed from Richard Cornwell to Joshua Sands March, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Warranty deed conveying lots bounding Henry Street and Fulton Street in Brooklyn from Richard Cornwell and his wife Mary Cornwell to Joshua Sands March, witnessed by William Ellsworth.
- Deed from Joshua Sands March to Thomas March, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Warranty deed conveying numerous lots of land lying in the Third Ward of Brooklyn from Joshua Sands March and his wife Magdalen March (née Middagh) to Thomas March, witnessed by John Vanderbilt.
- Deed from Thomas March to Joshua Sands March, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Warranty deed, as above, the parties reversed, the name of Sarah Ann March (née Sands) added to that of her husband Thomas March as a party to the deed, witnessed by Theodore Eames.
- Deed from Nicholas Luquer to Magdalen March, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Quit-claim deed conveying 16 lots on Brooklyn Heights from Nicholas Luquer and his wife Sarah Lea Luquer to Magdalen March (née Middagh) here described as "widow" (of Joshua S. March), signed and sealed by Nicholas and Sarah Luquer, witnessed by Sidney C. Herbert.
- Deed from William M. Sands to Clement D. March, 1846 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Deed conveying land at Sackets Harbor, Jefferson Co., NY from William M. Sands and his wife Elizabeth Sands (née Breese) to their nephew Clement D. March, as consideration for a debt owed to Thomas March (Clement's father, and William's brother-in-law) as William's surety in a judgement decided in favor of the U.S. government against William M. Sands and Thomas March in U.S. District Court for the Southern District of New York earlier in 1846, signed and sealed by all four parties, of Brooklyn, witnessed by John Greenwood.
- Deed from Clement D. March to John M. Sands, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Deed conveying the land at Sackets Harbor, Jefferson Co., NY, referred to in the prior deed (above), from Clement D. March to his cousin John Middagh Sands, signed and sealed by the four parties (as above) and by John M. Sands, witnessed by Alfred G. Stevens and Charles J. Lowrey and certified by John M. Hicks.
- Deed from Martha Middagh to John M. Sands, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Deed conveying four lots on Clinton Street in Brooklyn Heights from Martha Middagh (née Van Nostrand) to her son-in-law John M. Sands, the land having been received by previous deed from James Van Nostrand and abutting land of the Second Presbyterian Church and land formerly belonging to Valentine Swertcope and Aert Middagh, the deed signed and sealed by Martha Middagh, witnessed by Johule Smith and John M. Hicks.
- Deed from Edgar John Bartow to John M. Sands, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Deed conveying a lot on Clinton Street in Brooklyn Heights, adjacent to those referred to in the prior deed (above), from Edgar John Bartow and his wife Harriet Constable Bartow (née Pierrepont) to John M. Sands, signed and sealed by the Bartows, witnessed by James H. Cornwell and Thomas Stryker.
- Deed from Martha Middagh to John M. Sands, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Deed conveying a lot in Brooklyn Heights from Martha Middagh (née Van Nostrand) to her son-in-law John M. Sands, signed and sealed by Martha Middagh, witnessed by J. Lawrence Marcellus and Jacob Meserole.
- Lease and release from Aert Middagh to John Middagh, undated copy of 1770 original (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Lease and release conveying land lying southerly of "the road which leads down from Broucklin to the New York ferry" amounting to six acres, from Aert Middagh and his wife Magdalena Middagh (née Stryker) to their son John Middagh, the originals signed and sealed by Aert Middagh and witnessed by Jeronimus A. Remson and Engelbart Lott.
- Lease from Sarah Luquer to James Watters, Tobias Watters, and Walter Barre, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Lease conveying a lot at the corner of Henry Street and Poplar Street in Brooklyn from Sarah Luquer to James Watters, Tobias Watters, and Walter Barre, signed and sealed by all four, witnessed by Joseph Dean and R. D. Covert.
- Lease from Sarah Luquer to James Watters, Tobias Watters, and Walter Barre, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Lease conveying a lot on Henry Street in Brooklyn, the parties same as above, signed by them and witnessed by Edward M.M. Clarke.
- Lease from S.B.M. Sands to Thomas H. Redding and Peter H. Powell, 1830 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Lease conveying a lot at the corner of Fulton Street and "Bugbie's Alley" in Brooklyn from S.B.M. Sands (Samuel B.M. Sands) to Thomas H. Redding and Peter H. Powell, signed and sealed by the parties and witnessed by John Wortman.
- Lease from Nicholas Luquer to Nathaniel Gove, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Lease conveying a lot on the corner of Middagh Street and Henry Street in Brooklyn from Nicholas Luquer to Nathaniel Gove, signed and sealed by the parties and witnessed by J. March.
- Lease from Samuel B.M. Sands to Thomas H. Redding and John Wortman, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Lease conveying a lot at the corner of Fulton Street and "Buckbee's Alley" in Brooklyn, from Samuel B.M. Sands and his wife Magdalen Sands (née Middagh) to Thomas H. Redding and John Wortman, signed and sealed by the parties and witnessed by John McClusky.
- Lease from Magdalen Sands to James W. Burtis, 1836 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Lease conveying a lot with dwelling and store near the corner of Fulton Street and Middagh Street in Brooklyn for 15 years, from Magdalen Sands (as widow of Samuel B.M. Sands) to James W. Burtis, signed and sealed by the parties and witnessed by A.M. Van Nostrand.
- Leases and release from March, Henshaw and Gracie to Peck, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Two leases (1841) and a release (1850) conveying a lot at the corner of Fulton Street and Henry Street in Brooklyn from Joshua S. March and his wife Magdalen March (née Middagh), Charles J. Henshaw and his wife Cornelia Henshaw (née Middagh), and William R. Gracie and his wife Sarah Gracie (née Middagh) to James W. Peck and Robert W. Peck of New York City, signed and sealed by all parties, witnessed by Edward Copland and Thomas Bradlee, the Release witnessed by Charles J. Lowrey.
- Lease from the estate of Cornelia Henshaw to John M. Sands, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Assignment of lease conveying the right of Henry H. Cox (as trustee to the estate of Cornelia Henshaw, wife of Charles J. Henshaw) re: part of a lease of 1846 made by the Common Council of the City of Brooklyn, to John M. Sands, signed by Cox, witnessed by Edward C. Henshaw, Johule Smith, and John M. Hicks.
- Lease from John M. Sands to John Wortman, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Lease conveying a lot at the corner of Fulton Street and "Buckbee's Alley" in Brooklyn from John M. Sands to John Wortman, signed and sealed by both parties, witnessed by J. Lawrence Marcellus.
- Release from William Laurence of New York City to Samuel B.M. Sands, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Release of Mortgaged Premises conveying a lot on Fulton Street in Brooklyn from William Laurence of New York City to Samuel B.M. Sands and his wife Magdalen Sands (née Middagh), signed by Laurence, witnessed by Russel C. Wheeler.
- Agreement between Jacob Brantingham and Aquila B. Stout and Joshua S. March, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Articles of Agreement, made between Jacob Brantingham and Aquila B. Stout and Joshua S. March, the latter two men to purchase a block of 34 lots in Brooklyn from Brantingham, the block being part of the property of Nicholas Luquer, signed by the principal parties.
- Release from Coles family to Joshua S. March, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 16)